>> i've got the marshmallows.
>> i've got the graham crackers.
>> we'll wait here while you get
the firewood so we can make
S'mores.
>> now it is so nice to finally
See you two getting along.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
>> great!
>> is he gone?
>> yep.
>> this is your fault!
>> grandpa only turns 60 once.
I had his party totally wired.
>> you chose his birthday wish?
>> and how is he supposed to
Make one without a cake
that you were supposed to get?
>> uh, excuse me, full-time hero
here.
When do i have time to go get
some dumb old cake?
You were supposed to do it.
Anyway, it's no big deal.
>> for grandpa it is.
>> fine!
Play you to see who goes.
Rock, paper, scissors--on 3.
>> you are so on.
You always lose.
>> 1, 2--
ok, this can't be good.
Gwen!
>> ben? Gwen?
[captioning made possible by
Turner entertainment group]
>> ¶ it started when an alien
Device did what it did
and stuck itself upon his wrist
With secrets that it hid
now he's got super powers
He's no ordinary kid
he's ben 10!
So if you see him, you might be
in for a big surprise
He'll turn into an alien
before your very eyes
He's slimy, creepy, fast, and
strong
He's every shape and size
he's ben 10!
With all new powers
he's on the case
Fighting off evil
from earth or space
He'll never stops till he
makes them pay
'cause he's the baddest kid
to ever save the day
Ben 10! ¶
>> uh!
Uh.
>> hey, ben.
Looking good!
>> yo, ben 10-k, keep up the
awesome job!
>> 10 what?
>> whoa!
Hero of heroes, ben ten
thousand.
Is that really me?
>> more like, was you.
>> hey, tennyson, long time no
see.
>> do i know you?
>> prepare for my revenge!
>> oh, yeah?
Well, why don't you prepare to
See why they call me hero of--
yaaah!
Ooh.
Uh, maybe we could talk about
This?
>> kemo char!
>> ok, will someone tell me what
the heck's going on here?
>> is that xlr8?
>> looks like the work of animo.
I'll run a dna analysis back at
headquarters.
And send them back now.
>> whoa, you're me, right?
And it looks like i'm new and
improved.
This is so cool that i'm so
cool!
Did you say, "headquarters"?
I have my own headquarters!
>> i don't have time for this!
>> so when can you catch me up
On my other 9,990 heroes?
>> hmm.
How about...Never?!
>> you could lose the attitude,
You know.
Wait a minute.
You're me?
Gwen?
>> actually, i've been going by
"gwendolyn" since college.
>> college?
Ivy league?
Do i have a master's?
>> look, i didn't bring you here
To find out about your future.
I came back to bring ben.
>> so, why nab me?
>> i remembered ben's listening
Skills sort of stunk.
Grabbing you was the only way i
Knew he'd come.
>> so time-travel is no big deal
Now?
>> you just need to know the
Right spell to create the right
kind of portal.
>> i know magic?
How wicked is that!
What else do i know how to do?
Did i ever get my black belt?
>> hello!
Forget you.
This is about me.
>> he's right.
>> tell me i didn't grow up to
start agreeing with mr. Dweeb
All the time.
>> ben 10,000 needs his help.
>> i seem pretty tough.
What could a cool superhero like
Me need anyway?
>> ben 10,000 may have mastered
The secrets of the omnitrix, but
it still doesn't make him
Prepared for everything.
There's a crisis looming even he
Can't solve alone.
>> danger alert!
Sector 15-d.
>> what's in sector 15-d?
>> fort dna-x, earth's massive
genetic depository with dna
Samples from across the galaxy.
>> dr. Animo!
That's the crisis, right?
That's why i'm here.
He made that robot-rhino dude,
and now he's doing something
Else.
It's time to give the doctor a
Double-dose of ben medicine.
Come on, i'll give us a lift.
Aw, man!
Can't this thing power up faster
In the future?
>> ooh!
>> gwendolyn, i thought that was
you.
>> and us.
>> well, i see someone finally
Figured out how to work their
time portal.
>> grandpa!
>> now this is what i call a
Great gift, seeing you 2 again.
>> don't you still see us?
>> well, i--i see gwendolyn a
lot.
>> it's great seeing you, too.
But the same shirt?
Grandpa, it was 20 years out of
style 20 years ago.
>> hey, when you find a look
that works.
>> grandpa, we need a ride.
>> fort dna-x.
>> hop in.
>> whoa!
It's totally teched-out.
>> you ain't seen nothin' yet!
Hit it, grandpa.
>> so, where do i sleep?
>> in your fancy headquarters.
Where else?
You're too good to stay with us
anymore.
>> guess you just have other
priorities.
Well, here we are.
>> you coming, grandpa?
>> oh, no, no.
You haven't needed my help for
A long time.
Just make sure you say good-bye
Before gwendolyn sends you back.
>> time to go four arms and show
Ben 10,000 where it all begins.
>> aargh!
>> yeah, with you messing up
again.
>> what?!
>> aah!
>> oh, i was gonna go four arms,
too.
Great minds must think alike.
>> i don't think so.
Now go!
>> no one is going anywhere!
>> i see you brought help.
You're going to need it.
For every one of your 10,000
heroes, i will steal enough dna
To create 10,000 monstrous
minions.
>> oh, yeah?
Think again.
>> kemo chas!
>> stay out of my way!
>> oh, hey, you can't--
i mean, i can't do that to me!
>> shouldn't we help or
something?
>> no. He prefers it this way.
>> hey, i'm missing all the
Action.
>> wow! I rock!
What do you call that other one?
Loogie man?
Spitter?
>> they're not pets!
I don't name them anymore.
>> aw, but that was half the
Fun.
>> aah!
>> did we detect a cry for help?
The galactic enforcers have
Arrived.
>> show's over, guys.
>> it's a big world, ben.
You could always save a couple
Of the bad guys for us, you
know.
>> what would be the point?
But since you're here, how about
Bringing animo back to the
null-void chamber for me.
>> yeah, sure.
Anything to help.
>> gwendolyn, i'll meet you back
at headquarters.
>> guess you got me now.
There's nothing i can do.
Heh heh.
>> so animo's been around this
Whole time?
>> he escaped a few years back.
I wasn't sure if he was going to
show his ugly face again.
But now, it looks like he won't
be a problem anymore.
>> woof, woof, woof, woof, woof.
>> what about vilgax?
>> last i saw of him, i left him
in pieces.
It wasn't pretty for anyone.
'nuff said.
>> whoa, i really need to
lighten up.
>> mr. Vilgax, so nice you could
Rejoin me.
>> whoa!
This is my headquarters?
Awesome!
I must chill out here a lot.
>> there's no time.
I'm always patrolling the
planet, thus, ben has no need to
Hang out here.
>> ok, tell me i didn't just
Say, "thus."
don't i have any fun anymore?
>> you'll learn soon enough,
being me is not about fun.
Now wait here for gwendolyn, and
don't touch a thing!
>> hey, look
>> he said not to touch
Anything.
>> why should i listen to me?
You never do.
>> hey!
Yeah!
Woo-hoo!
Whoa-ho!
Guess i should have told her to
Duck, huh?
>> get off that board now!
>> what?
I don't even smile when i
Terrorize gwen anymore?
Heh, you're even worse than i
Thought.
Cool move, huh?
Want to race?
>> no!
Those days are over.
>> well, what i'm over is being
A hero if this is how i turn
out.
I am such a jerk!
>> danger alert.
Sector 1-a centric.
Danger alert.
>> what is it?
>> my business, not yours!
Get the portal open and get
Them home.
>> well, i'm not going.
You brought me here for a
reason, and i bet it's what's
Going on in sector 1-a centric.
Is it far away?
>> it's 61 stories below us.
Ooh, the null-void projector!
>> it ends now, animo!
>> oh, but it's only just
beginning.
>> vilgax!
>> animo's trying to open the
null-void chamber.
>> and free everyone me and
grandpa ever captured.
Vilgax?!
He's mine.
Take animo.
>> with pleasure.
>> aw, man!
Uh! Take that!
Uh!
>> get out of here.
>> when are you gonna get it
through your thick skull?
If this is your fight, it's my
fight, too.
>> well, then, this might help.
>> hey, i don't have to be ben
Anymore.
>> you won't keep me away for
long!
>> you think you can destroy me?
I analyzed every one of your
Aliens...
And had animo program their
Moves into my new dna.
Nothing you can do will surprise
Me anymore.
>> get your claws off my
Grandson!
>> help the gwens.
They're by the null void.
>> you can't protect the null
Void and yourselves at the same
time.
>> oh, yeah?
Meena goh!
>> ooh!
>> oh!
>> when did you get that?
>> a lot can happen in 20 years.
Come on, let's show him what we
tennyson's are made of.
>> he may know how all your
aliens fight, but does he know
What ben tennyson can do?
I just hope after all this time,
You haven't forgotten, too.
>> you're finished, both of you!
>> maybe it's time i did start
fighting like you.
>> eh, your weak, human form?
What a novelty!
Are you finally ready to
surrender?
>> actually, i was getting ready
to settle this the old-fashioned
Way.
Follow my lead.
Woo!
Come on!
>> if this is your attempt to
Stop me, it's pathetic
and pointless.
>> woo-hoo!
Ha ha!
Woo!
>> hey, what do you call this
Guy?
>> i don't name--uh, i don't
Know.
Absolute zero?
>> boring!
How about articguana?
>> cool!
>> twin stuff, call me titan.
>> interdamoto laborator.
>> where do you think you're
Going?
>> by the way, that black belt
You were wondering about, you
got it years ago, and it's
Come in handy many times.
>> happy birthday, grandpa!
>> well, thanks.
Having you all here is the best
80th birthday present i could
ever have.
>> sorry, ben.
Danger alert.
Maneuvo circus freaks are in
quadrant 92-j.
>> hey, can't you guys see it's
my grandpa's birthday?
You handle it.
>> really?
I mean, of course.
Ultimos out.
>> the crisis was never vilgax
Or animo, was it?
Your ben just needed a major
Attitude adjustment, huh?
>> yeah. I couldn't have grandpa
Celebrate his 80th birthday
without him.
Look, gwen, i know your ben can
be a major dweeb, but enjoy him
While you can.
Now come on, the portal's ready,
And there's another birthday
party you guys got to get to.
>> wait!
You never told me the secrets of
The watch, how i don't have to
go ben.
>> trust me, you're gonna want
to go ben.
Thanks for making me realize
that.
Oh, here.
Take this.
>> what is it?
>> something i should have
Gotten grandpa 20 years ago.
>> guys, it's closing!
>> see ya.
>> and i guess we're gonna be
Ya.
>> ben? Gwen?
>> surprise!
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Grandpa!
>> i--i mean we got you a cake.
Happy birthday, grandpa.
Woo-hoo! Make a wish, grandpa!
[captioning made possible by
Turner entertainment group]
[captioned by the national
Captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--]