>> 500 stores, 72 restaurants,
48 movie screens, an indoor
rollercoaster!
>> we could just spend the
whole summer here.
This mall has everything.
>> halt in the name of mall
security!
>> including their own police
Force.
>> looks like the rent-a-cops
could use a little help.
A hero's work is never done.
>>
[captioning made possible by
Turner entertainment group]
>> ¶ it started when
an alien device did what it did
And stuck itself
upon his wrist
with secrets that it hid
Now he's got super powers
he's no ordinary kid
he's ben 10 ¶
>> ¶ ben 10
>> ¶ so if you see him
you might be in
For a big surprise
he'll turn into an alien
before your very eyes
He's funny, freaky, fast
and strong
he's every shape and size
He's ben 10 ¶
>> ¶ ben 10
>> ¶ all new powers
He's on the case
fighting all evil
from earth or space
He'll never stop till it's ok
'cause he's the baddest kid
to ever save the day
Ben 10 ¶
>> ¶ ben 10
>> ¶ 10, 10, 10
>>
>> they let loose some kind of
rabid dog to cover their tracks.
Get him.
They must be trying to
escape in that rv.
Cut him off.
>> uh, looking for something,
officer?
>> nice going last night, hero.
Not only did you let the
robbers get away, but because
They thought your furry butt
was inside, they played
demolition derby with the rust
Bucket.
>>
hey, the mall's gonna pay for
All the repairs, and it bought
us a few more days here while
grandpa waits for the parts.
You should be thanking me.
>> i guess you're right.
Nice job, wildmutt.
The amazing sublimino, master
of hypnosis, last day?
Cool! Let's check it out.
>> gee, and to think we almost
missed him.
>> ladies and gentlemen,
Presenting sublimino, the
master of hypnosis.
Behold sublimino.
I am about to take you on a
journey through that mysterious
Realm known as the mind.
First, i shall require some
volunteers.
>> give me a break.
Only somebody with half a brain
can be hypnotized.
>> hey, here's a volunteer for
you.
>> me? Forget it!
>> what's the matter?
Afraid you don't have half a
brain?
>> now, clear your minds.
Focus only on this pocket watch
as it swings back and forth.
Your eyelids are feeling heavy.
You are falling into a deep
sleep.
>>
>> major blackmail time.
>> now you are in my power.
When you open your eyes, you
will all become newborn babies.
>>
>> now you are all chickens in
a barnyard.
>>
>> why is ben acting like a
chicken?
>> it's my early christmas
Present.
>> you are a ballerina.
You are a ferocious grizzly
Bear.
>> arrr!
>> this is so funny!
>> and you, my lad, you are an
alien.
>> joke's over.
>> ben, no!
>> you are ruining the
performance!
>> sorry.
My cousin had to run to the
little aliens' room.
>> take me to your leader.
Your will is my command.
>> oh, this is so embarrassing.
>> wait. Wait.
Here's my favorite part.
>> more grapes, master?
>> oh, man.
>> hey, take it easy.
You're gonna give me split ends.
>> what?
What just happened?
>> too bad you snapped out of
It when the omnitrix timed out.
I was going to have you do a
hot oil conditioning treatment
Next.
>> yeah?
Well, that's why they created
Erase buttons.
>> give that back!
>> all right, that's a wrap on
The video.
It's been a long day, and we
could all use some shut-eye.
Lights out.
>> why can't you just leave me
alone?
>> doofus.
>> uh.
>> hey, you ok, ben?
You don't seem as peppy as
usual.
>> just a little tired, that's
all.
>> whoa. What happened?
>> somebody stole the motor
from the sea dragon ride.
Probably a prank by some punk
Kids.
>> what do you make of this?
>> what? I didn't do it.
I swear.
Hey, i'm not the only alien in
the galaxy, you know.
>> uh, ben, where are you going
at this time of night?
Hello. Earth to doofus.
I asked you a question.
Wait. You can't go out like
That.
>> he must be sleepwalking.
>> halt in the name of mall
Security!
>> ben, wake up!
You're sleepwalking!
>> it's no use, gwen.
He can't hear you.
He probably has no idea what
he's doing.
>> so what else is new?
>> i'd better get up there.
>>
>> look!
>> time sure flies when you go
alien.
>> who are you?
What happened to the guy that
looked like a walking
Chandelier?
Oh, well.
Who cares, as long as you do
What i say?
Now get out of here before the
cops see you!
>> oh, man, what a weird dream.
Whoa! Oh, man!
>> despite last night's bizarre
Attack and other burglaries,
the mall representative had
this to say.
>> this was an isolated
incident.
The mall is open for business.
Shopper safety is our number
one priority.
>> so why would i go alien and
Then steal bizarre stuff like a
rollercoaster motor and a big
clock?
>> well, sleepwalkers are in a
hyper dream state.
Nothing makes sense in a dream.
>> yeah, but most sleepwalkers
don't have a watch full of
alien heroes at their control.
>> well, gwen's got a point.
We're gonna have to keep you
awake and away from people
Until we can figure out how to
stop your midnight strolls.
>> hey! What'd you do that for?
>> just doing my job.
>> aah!
Aah!
Ahh!
Hey, you're enjoying this,
aren't you?
>> now, why would you say that?
>> grandpa, wake up.
It's your shift.
>> awake, my slaves.
Awake and serve your master
sublimino.
>> gwen, turn down the heat,
Will you?
I'm cooking over here.
Ben!
Ben, listen to me.
You've got to snap out of this.
>> you're under some kind of
Hypnotic spell or something.
>> you two, get away from that
thing.
Everybody out. Move! Move! Move!
>> this was an isolated
incident.
The mall is open for business.
Shopper safety is our number
one priority.
>> so sublimino plants post-
hypnotic suggestions in his
volunteers, turning them into
His army of thieves.
>> but the sound of the
omnitrix timing out snaps ben
Out of the trance.
>> aah! But why have me steal
All that weird stuff?
>> i don't know, but sublimino
sure does.
We need to find him, and fast.
>> this was an isolated
incident.
The mall is open for business.
Shopper safety is our number
one priority.
>> yes, yes, you said that
already.
But i'm saying your shoppers
Are in danger.
>> this was an isolated
incident.
That mall is open for business.
Shopper safety is our number
one priority.
>> ok, this is getting us
nowhere.
>> well done.
All the preparations are
complete.
It's showtime.
>> hey, ben, wake up.
Where's gwen?
>> oh, mom, i'm too tired to go
To school.
>> i've got the perfect
solution to your sleepwalking
Problem.
If you can't touch the
omnitrix, you can't go alien.
>> where'd you get those?
>> survivalists "r" us.
They have a very extensive
Selection.
>> i don't know about this,
gwen.
>> what could go wrong?
>> greetings, mall rats.
I am sublimino, master of
Hypnosis.
You are all about to take a
journey through that mysterious
Realm known as the mind.
No need to volunteer.
Now all of you will obey me
Forever!
>> your eyelids are getting
very heavy.
You are falling into a deep
Sleep.
>> huh?
A giant hypno-watch?
Ha!
No way that'll ever work.
Or maybe it will.
Don't look at the clock.
>>
>> gwen, wake up.
Where's the key?
>> all arise and obey my every
Command every minute of every
day.
Now, bring me all the riches of
This place.
>> wait, gwen, come back.
>> yes, yes.
First the mall, then all of
america.
There will be no stopping me.
>> you may control every last
person, but what about a plant?
>> you there, plant guy, stop.
Obey me.
I command you, obey me!
Don't just stand there.
Stop that plant thing.
>> emergency brake.
Uh! Uh!
Hey, how come gwen gets to
drive?
Grandpa! Gwen!
Hang on.
Whoa!
Going up.
Show's over.
>> trim that hedge!
>>
>> aah!
>> you!
I will put you in a trance from
which you will never recover!
>> aah!
>> give that back, you brat!
>> everyone, wake up!
You're all free!
>> no, no, no!
It isn't fair.
>> now who's the baby?
>> looks like your time is up.
>> nice job, ben. Ben?
>> your eyelids are feeling
heavy.
You are falling into a
Deep sleep.
>> hey, ben, what are you doing
back there?
>> uh, nothing.
You are now completely under
my power.
>> yes, master.
Your wish is my command.
>> oh, cool! It worked!
Now, get me some ice cream.
>> yes, master.
>> this summer just got a whole
Lot better.
Now, give it to me.
>> yes, master.
>> hey!
>> ha, psych!
You want anything else, master?
>> just a different cousin.
>>
[captioning made possible by
[captioned by the national
captioning institute
--Www.Ncicap.Org--]